[Music]
let's discover and explore reports in
business Central 2025 release wave 1 in
this video I'm going to show you three
different ways you can do that with the
new experience in the report
Explorer um directly from our
documentation in Microsoft learn or from
the report help on the request page so
let's dive into business Central and
look at report
Explorer you can get to the report
Explorer in a number of ways for
instance if you open tell me search
you'll find a link here to exploring
reports so that's the first way the
second way is to use the symbol here for
opening the RO Explorer and then from
here explore more roles and here under
reports and Analysis that is the
shortcut to the report Explorer and the
final option if I just go back to the
road Center
here is uh simply to use the link on top
of all Road centers all reports this
also takes you directly to the report
Explorer let me start by collapsing all
the different roles what you see here on
the screen are different what we call
departmental roles centers these are
meant to be showcasing functionality for
different roles in an organization and
if I just pick one of them finance and
explore this this opens up whoa lots of
reports let's collapse all of them and
just see so this opens up the the report
Explorer or the road Explorer with
different topics so we can see Power pi
receivables and so on and if we then
choose the ellipses here and expand all
of these this is your overview of all
the reporting capabilities that exist
within Finance as a new thing here in
wave one we uh if you hover over a link
here you either get one of these little
information icons or let's just pick one
of the other ones or you might get one
of these uh opening a new window let me
just show the icon first the information
if I choose this
um I can now see first of all what the
full caption or the title of the report
is but I can also read more about what
this report is so I can actually without
even opening the report I can read more
about what this report is
about and uh you notice that the same
icon that you saw on on the other report
open a new window here appears on this
little uh information popup so let's try
to explore this report further and um a
new thing here in the in the business
Central as in in wave one is that this
opens up in a new window which means the
actual Explorer here keeps being open
and therefore you can explore multiple
reports from that page now this is um
this is the just one way I can then
preview this report or whatever I like
when I'm done with this exploration I
can close the window and I'm back to the
report
Explorer and as I mentioned if there's
no information icon uh there will always
be this open a new window the difference
like why would this have one and this
one would not that's just a matter of
whether there's a teaching tiip defined
on the object here compared to this one
so this if fixed asset posting group net
change uh report does not have such
a text defined whereas the fixed asset
register report does have it so that was
the first way of exploring
reports the second way is directly in
the business Central documentation on
Microsoft learn uh the the easiest way I
find the report documentation is through
an AKA link let me show you what that is
about business Central documentation
have many of these AKA links that called
AKA links because they all start with
aka.ms something typically BC and then
something and for the for this link BC
analytics if I choose
this it will open up the overview of
everything in analytics in business
Central and here in the table of content
I can choose build-in reports and choose
the first link report overview and this
article gives a complete overview almost
complete overview of the reports that
exist in business Central these are
ordered by the the the functional area
so if you're interested in say sales
reports you can choose that and that
gives you um this table with first of
all scenario so an analytical scenario
of of the first report what you can use
it for uh the second link here is a link
directly to business Central so you can
open the report directly in business
Central from documentation if you use
this little tip of Control Plus selects
when you when you select the link it
will open up in a new window so you
still keep the exploration page here
open and finally each of these come with
an article that describe um the usage of
this particular report so for instance
it it's there's some description about
what the report shows and then there are
use cases described for different
personas that could be where this report
could be of interest and then
finally down here there's a try the
report link if I use this link I will
just go back to business Central I will
again use this control key plus select
to open this in a new window and this
will then open the request page for the
customer top 10 list Excel um in a new
window let's just have a look and now um
I can try the report here the third
option of discovering report content
let's just go back to the report
Explorer and uh and open a report from
there and let's choose the fixed asset
Book value one report again now I just
open it directly from the report
Explorer and I get the request page if
you for many of these reports if you
choose the title here or caption it will
open up something called a teaching tip
this also works even if you have turned
off teaching tiip by default you can
still get to the teaching tiip by
clicking that uh
link if you want to dive further and you
don't have to do this but you could also
just open the help Pane and the same
text will appear over here if that text
have been defined on the object on the
report report and finally there is a way
here directly from the help Paine to go
back to the business Central
documentation for the giving report and
if I then choose this link I now get the
documentation for the fixed asset Book
value report again with use case and
description and so on so that's how how
the exploration and discoverability of
reports come hand in hand both in the
business Central role Explorer in the
request page in the help Pane and in the
documentation in Microsoft learn